<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Pritpal Singh</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pritpal Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.124.1</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 01:29:35 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CompileX - Online Coding Platform</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/07_compile-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 01:29:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/07_compile-x/</guid>
      <description>CompileX is a comprehensive online coding platform designed to empower developers of all skill levels. This platform offers a space to write and execute code, practice coding skills, and compete in coding contests.
✨ Features ⚔️ Coding Playground Write, compile, and execute code in a user-friendly editor. Support for at least one compiled language. Real-time error feedback and performance metrics. 🏋️‍♂️ Coding Arena Practice with pre-existing coding problems or upload new problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InsightsiQ - Data-Driven Assistant for E-Commerce Sellers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/asdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 01:29:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/asdf/</guid>
      <description>Overview InsightsiQ is a powerful, data-driven assistant designed to empower e-commerce sellers with actionable insights. By simplifying complex data into a comprehensive dashboard, InsightsiQ helps sellers make informed decisions, boost sales, and contribute to the overall growth of the e-commerce platform.
Problem Statement In the fast-paced world of e-commerce, sellers often struggle to make data-driven decisions due to the overwhelming volume of information. Understanding market trends, keeping track of competitive activities, and identifying international opportunities can be daunting tasks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Computer Vision Model to play Hill Climb Racing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/03_hillclimbracing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 01:29:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/03_hillclimbracing/</guid>
      <description>This project aims to create a gesture-based control system for playing the classic game Hill Climb Racing using hand gestures. Leveraging computer vision techniques through OpenCV, users can control the game without traditional input devices.
About the Project Description: Created a gesture-based control system for playing the classic game Hill Climb Racing using hand gestures. This project utilized computer vision techniques through OpenCV to detect and interpret hand gestures, allowing users to control the game without traditional input devices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CAPEC Based Web Attacks Classifier</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/01_capec/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 01:29:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/01_capec/</guid>
      <description>This machine learning project focuses on the identification and classification of web attacks by leveraging advanced multilabel machine learning algorithms. The primary objective is to categorize web attacks into Common Attack Pattern Enumeration and Classification categories, providing a comprehensive understanding of the threats posed to web applications. The project employs a diverse set of multilabel machine learning algorithms, including but not limited to Binary Relevance, Random Forest, Label Powerset, Multi-Output Classifier, and LightGBM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GoChat!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/06_cli_based_chatapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 01:29:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/06_cli_based_chatapp/</guid>
      <description>A CLI Messaging App made with GoLang This is a simple command-line interface (CLI) messaging application written in Go. It allows users to send messages between each other, broadcast messages to all users, and view message logs.
You can run this on replit as well, here.
Key Components User Struct The User struct represents a user with a unique ID and their message log.
type User struct { ID int Log []string } Message Struct The Message struct represents a message with sender ID, receiver ID, and content.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IPL Win Probability Prediction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/02_ipl_prob/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 01:29:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/02_ipl_prob/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever checked the live score of any cricket match on google? I bet you have. And if you are a cricket fan, you would have noticed google offers a live win probability prediction for any cricket match. My inner child (and my 2rd yr Minor Project Deadline) motivated me to develop an end-to-end machine learning project using Python to predict the probability of an IPL cricket team winning a match given an instance of the match.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Threaded Proxy Server</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/05_multithreaded_proxyserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 01:29:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/05_multithreaded_proxyserver/</guid>
      <description>This project is implemented using C and Parsing of HTTP referred from Proxy Server Project Theory Introduction How did we implement Multi-threading? Used Semaphore instead of Condition Variables and pthread_join() and pthread_exit() function. pthread_join() requires us to pass the thread id of the the thread to wait for. Semaphore’s sem_wait() and sem_post() doesn’t need any parameter. So it is a better option. Motivation/Need of Project To Understand → The working of requests from our local computer to the server.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tetris Game with Hand Gesture Control </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/04_tetris/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 01:29:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/04_tetris/</guid>
      <description>About the Project This project implements a Tetris game using Python with the added functionality of controlling the game using hand gestures detected from a webcam feed. The game utilizes the pygame library for graphics, cv2 for webcam access, and mediapipe for hand gesture detection. Players can control the movement of Tetris pieces by gesturing left, right, rotate, and fast-drop.
Control Flow Display the webcam feed using OpenCV. Dynamically adjust the fall speed of Tetris pieces based on gameplay time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Random Really Random?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/blog1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 01:29:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/blog1/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever paused while using a &amp;ldquo;random&amp;rdquo; function on your computer and thought, &amp;ldquo;Is this truly random, or is my machine just pretending?&amp;rdquo;
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t, don’t worry—you’re in the company of most people who haven&amp;rsquo;t taken a deep dive into this existential query. But today, we&amp;rsquo;re peeling back the layers of randomness to discover if our machines are indeed rolling the dice or just pulling a fast one on us.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of File Systems: From FAT to ZFS and Beyond</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/blog2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 01:29:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/blog2/</guid>
      <description>Break down real-world scenarios where specific data structures like graphs, trees, or hash maps are crucial, and how choosing the right one can dramatically improve performance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>$who-am-i</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about_me/</guid>
      <description>why you might want to go on a date with me give me a job! My name is Pritpal (प्रित्पाल/ਪ੍ਰਿਤਪਾਲ) Singh, however I am famous among my friends as Preeto. You can use the pronouns: he/him/his when you talk about me in English.
I am currently seeking opportunities in the field of AI and Machine Learning.
In 2020, when the world was shut, I got lucky and was selected to attend an apprenticeship program by Intel, AI for Youth.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
